<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE site_info [
	<!ENTITY % XMLSpecial PUBLIC "-//W3C//ENTITIES Special for XML//EN" "characters.ent">
	%XMLSpecial;
]>
<site_info>
	<title>Faulkner at Virginia</title>
	<index>
		<center><img src="maintitle.gif"></center>
		<p>This is the test version of our project.  Please don't share its URL with anyone else &mdash;  it's running on a server that can&rsquo;t 
			handle much traffic.  But please do look and listen and search and explore, and let me have the benefit of all your reactions  &mdash; errata in the
		transcripts you spot, problems with functionality or design elements you see, ideas for revisions, improvements, additions, &amp;c.  Thanks!  Steve
			Railton</p>
	</index>
	<browse>
		<list>
			<item>wfaudio01_1</item>
			<item>wfaudio01_2</item>
			<item>wfaudio02_1</item>
			<item>wfaudio02_2</item>
			<item>wfaudio03</item>
			<item>wfaudio04</item>
			<item>wfaudio05_1</item>
			<item>wfaudio05_2</item>
			<item>wfaudio06_1</item>
			<item>wfaudio06_2</item>
			<item>wfaudio07_1</item>
			<item>wfaudio07_2</item>
			<item>wfaudio08_1</item>
			<item>wfaudio08_2</item>
			<item>wfaudio09_1</item>
			<item>wfaudio09_2</item>
			<item>wfaudio10</item>
			<item>wfaudio11_1</item>
			<item>wfaudio11_2</item>
			<item>wfaudio12_1</item>
			<item>wfaudio12_2</item>
			<item>wfaudio12_3</item>
			<item>wfaudio13</item>
			<item>wfaudio14_1</item>
			<item>wfaudio14_2</item>
			<item>wfaudio15</item>
			<item>wfaudio16_1</item>
			<item>wfaudio16_2</item>
			<item>wfaudio17</item>
			<item>wfaudio18_1</item>
			<item>wfaudio18_2</item>
			<item>wfaudio18_3</item>
			<item>wfaudio19_1</item>
			<item>wfaudio19_2</item>
			<item>wfaudio20_1</item>
			<item>wfaudio20_2</item>
			<item>wfaudio21</item>
			<item>wfaudio22_1</item>
			<item>wfaudio22_2</item>
			<item>wfaudio23_1</item>
			<item>wfaudio23_2</item>
			<item>wfaudio24_1</item>
			<item>wfaudio24_2</item>
			<item>wfaudio25</item>
			<item>wfaudio26_1</item>
			<item>wfaudio26_2</item>
			<item>wfaudio27</item>
			<item>wfaudio28_1</item>
			<item>wfaudio28_2</item>
			<item>wfaudio29_1</item>
			<item>wfaudio29_2</item>
			<item>wfaudio30_1</item>
			<item>wfaudio30_2</item>
			<item>wfaudio31</item>
			<item>wfaudio32</item>
		</list>
		<text>
			<h2>Browse</h2>
		</text>
	</browse>
	
	<page id="essays" slug="Essays" title="Essays on Faulkner">
		<section id="virginia" title="Virginia in the Late 1950s">
			
			<div id="essay_content">
			<h1 class="uppercase">Virginia in the Late 1950s</h1>
			
			<p><img src="uva50s01.jpg" align="left" hspace="8" border="0" alt="DETAIL: 1957 YEARBOOK PHOTO" title="DETAIL: 1957 YEARBOOK PHOTO" />In February 1957, when William Faulkner arrived in Charlottesville to occupy his position as Virginia&#8217;s first Writer-in-Residence, &#8220;Mr. Jefferson&#8217;s University&#8221; was 132 years old. Its first students matriculated in March 1825: 123 undergraduates, all white males.  There were almost five thousand UVA students by the 1956-1957 academic year, but they were still mostly white and male.  The Nursing School&#8217;s students were all female, the Education School was largely female, and there were a few women students in the graduate Schools of Law, Medicine and Arts and Sciences, but officially there were no women students in the College of Arts &amp; Sciences until 1969, and the College was not fully co-educational until the Class of 1976 arrived in 1972.  There actually are a few women pictured among the college students in the 1957 and 1958 editions of <em>Corks and Curls</em>, the school yearbook, but they might have been daughters of faculty members; during those years Mary Washington College, in Fredericksburg, was officially designated the state&#8217;s school for women.  (When Faulkner traveled there to speak in April 1957 he would still have been considered &#8220;in-residence&#8221; at UVA.)  A large number of the questions from Faulkner&#8217;s UVA audiences come from women; in May 1957 he met with a group identified as &#8220;Wives of Law School Students,&#8221; and &#8220;Wives&#8221; were invited to his session with the English Department faculty the same month, but since women only made up about 3% of the total student body, it is not clear who the women were during the other sessions, especially the classroom sessions.  Several were certainly graduate students in English (three are identified by name in his session with Stevenson&#8217;s English 32), many were interested residents of Charlottesville or Albemarle County, still others may have been the wives of faculty members sitting in on classes when Faulkner was present.  These presence of these women suggests the environment at UVA wasn&#8217;t as &#8220;male&#8221; as it looks in the records.  To my ear, at least, the women&#8217;s voices we hear on the tapes don&#8217;t sound shy or hesitant about being part of the conversation.</p>

			<p><a href="#corks5704" class="inline"><img src="uva50s02.jpg" align="left" hspace="8" border="0" alt="DETAIL: PHOTO OF DELTA KAPPA EPSILON IN 1957 YEARBOOK" title="DETAIL: PHOTO OF DELTA KAPPA EPSILON IN 1957 YEARBOOK" /></a>On the other hand, I don&#8217;t hear any recognizably &#8220;black&#8221; voices among the hundreds of people who ask Faulkner questions, and it seems likely that there were no blacks in any of his audiences here (though one man on the tapes identifies himself as an Indian national).  Thanks to the series of legal battles fought by the NAACP in the courtroom in the years leading up to the Supreme Court&#8217;s <em>Brown v Board of Education</em> decision, in the 1950s African American students began attending UVA in very small numbers: a few in the Law School, in Education and in Engineering.  I saw no sign of these students in <em>Corks and Curls</em> from the years Faulkner was here; the only black faces in those yearbooks belong either to the entertainers who came to town for the big weekends (Duke Ellington, Lionel Hampton, Louis Armstrong, among others) or to the servants who worked for the fraternities (identified in the group photos simply by their first names).   A May 1957 editorial in the student newspaper, <em>The Cavalier Daily</em>, titled <a href="#cavdaily23" class="inline">&#8220;Desegregation At The University,&#8221;</a> refers to &#8220;the Negro students [now] enrolled,&#8221; but adds that there has not been any &#8220;social mixing between white and Negro&#8221; at UVA, &#8220;even when the two have attended dances together in Memorial Gymnasium.&#8221;  [CD,cavdaily22.txt]</p>

			<p><img src="uva50s03.jpg" align="left" hspace="8" border="0" alt="COVER: 1957 SPECTATOR JIM CROW ISSUE" title="COVER: 1957 SPECTATOR JIM CROW ISSUE" />The &#8220;Supreme Court decision&#8221; comes up several times in Faulkner&#8217;s sessions at UVA, and no one has to explain which decision is being referred to.  You can hear the discussions that follow for yourself.  I sense a good deal of anxiety in the room whenever this subject is brought up, but very little openness to the possibility of social transformation.  The large number of news articles about school integration struggles throughout the South on the front pages of <em>The Cavalier Daily</em> between Fall 1956 and Spring 1958 suggests that white students were very interested in how traditional southern racial patterns might be changing, but in those same issues there is no discussion of admitting black students to the College.  Although UVA never seems to be included in the category of &#8220;public schools,&#8221; a few voices were raised in the <em>CD</em> for school integration, belonging to some faculty members and one faculty wife (Sarah Boyle).  The paper defended the &#8220;Jim Crow Issue&#8221; published in May 1958 by <em>The Virginia Spectator</em>; in the issue this undergraduate monthly reprinted Faulkner&#8217;s <em>Life</em> magazine &#8220;Letter to the North&#8221; and listed him as the &#8220;moderator&#8221; of the debate staged between four newly-written articles, two pro-segregation and two pro-integration, none written by students (CD, 8 May 1957: 1, 2).  But most articles in the paper suggest how deeply the student body was loyal to the racial status quo. [CD,cavdaily13.txt]  When in May 1957 the <em>CD</em> decided to respond to a challenge from the Writer-in-Residence ñ &#8220;William Faulkner said yesterday, ëI&#8217;d like to see more undergraduates of this University express their opinions on topics of wide interest&#8217;&#8221;  (CD, 5 May 1957: 2) ñ by conducting a &#8220;Poll on Integration,&#8221; students were given only two plans to choose between, and as the paper said, &#8220;Both plans have a common goal ñ prevention of racial integration in the public schools.&#8221;  (CD, 15 May 1957: 2) The plan that called for delaying tactics defeated the one that advocated vigorous defiance of the federal courts by two-to-one, but while one student wrote &#8220;we must have complete integration&#8221; on his ballot (CD, 16 May 1957: 1) , and one student wrote the paper to complain that too few ballot boxes were available (CD, 17 May 1957: 2), no protests were registered about the narrow range of &#8220;opinions&#8221; the poll reflected.</p>

			<p><a href="uva50s04.jpg" title=""><img src="uva50s04.jpg" align="left" hspace="8" border="0" alt="DETAIL: 1958 YEARBOOK PHOTO" title="DETAIL: 1958 YEARBOOK PHOTO" /></a> One of the topics that Faulkner most frequently wants to give his own opinion about in the UVA sessions is &#8220;the pressure to conform&#8221; that he sees as among the most serious threats facing modern society.  He brought that concern with him to Virginia, but what he found at UVA probably only increased it.  These were what Robert Lowell called &#8220;the tranquilized Fifties,&#8221; and despite or because of Cold War fears about nuclear annihilation there was a widespread national longing for what journalists were calling &#8220;normalcy.&#8221;  Even so, the environment at UVA in the late 1950s exalted conformity ñ though the students called it &#8220;tradition.&#8221;  The suit jackets and ties that students wore to all classes and public events as a kind of uniform were the outward and visible sign of a community that was comfortable with the world that they found themselves in, and devoted to the rituals of the previous generations of students.  &#8220;Gentleman&#8221; was a word that resonated much more deeply with them than &#8220;intellectual&#8221; or &#8220;artist.&#8221;</p>

			<p><a href="javascript:Start3('faulknerABC.html')"><img src="uva50s05.jpg" align="left" hspace="8" border="0" alt="DETAIL: CD FAULKNER PHOTO" title="DETAIL: CD FAULKNER PHOTO" /></a>Faulkner&#8217;s picture appears twice in the 1957 <em>Corks and Curls</em>, in the &#8220;Features&#8221; section.   Judging by the yearbook&#8217;s annual emphases, however, the chief features of student life at UVA were fraternities, football games, and the three regularly occuring &#8220;big weekends&#8221; ñ Openings, Mid-Winters, and Easters, supplemented by other annual events like the Beaux Arts Ball. For each of the three &#8220;big&#8221; weekends <em>The Cavalier Daily</em> published expanded editions, allowing them to list all the women (from other schools, of course) who would be attending, along with the names of their UVA dates.  Again to judge by the yearbook&#8217;s photos, music and alcohol were the main ingredients of these weekends.  No one asked Faulkner during any of his sessions about Gowan Stevens, the character in <em>Sanctuary</em> who has just graduated from Virginia and can&#8217;t stop talking about how he&#8217;d &#8220;learned in a good school&#8221; how to drink, which turns out to mean how to get drunk; if Faulkner&#8217;s interrogators were embarrassed to bring Gowan up, though, the yearbook seems to celebrate displays of drunkenness.  This prevailing alcoholic culture makes it hard to know how to &#8220;read&#8221; the photograph <em>at left</em>, published on the front page of <em>The Cavalier Daily</em>'s "Mid-Winters Issue," which appeared the morning after Faulkner gave his speech exhorting Virginians to show the rest of the South the way toward integration ñ a picture of the Writer-in-Residence coming out of the liquor store with a paper bag in his hands (CD, 21 February 1958: 1).  Is it an attempt to undercut his message by suggesting it came out of a bottle of booze? or does it imply (especially since students would be stocking up their own bottles for the weekend) that Faulkner is &#8220;one of us&#8221;?  (The photo was taken by Ken Ringle, who discusses it in his essay on Faulkner at UVA; in the first issue of the <em>CD</em> after the weekend, the paper ran an editorial about the speech, expressing disappointment with Faulkner&#8217;s inadequacies as a speaker, but approving the way &#8220;Faulkner's proposal [for improving Negro education] offers the compromise between the dogmatism of the North and the South on the subject&#8221; [CD, 25 February 1958: 2...cavdaily22.txt].)</p>

			<p><a href="javascript:Start3('uvaenglish.html')"><img src="uvaenglisht.jpg" align="left" hspace="8" border="0" alt="DETAIL: ENGLISH DEPT IN 1960" title="DETAIL: ENGLISH DEPT IN 1960" /></a>Although probably only about half of the people who ask Faulkner questions on the tapes were UVA students, the most common setting for these sessions was an English Department class.  In 1957 and 1958 the department&#8217;s faculty were also all white and male.</p>

			<p>and centered on the traditional   English lit, etc.  And one time F&#8217;s name appears in catalogue
			questionnaire on when F first studied?
			Can identify the time by large number of questions on symbols
			To give an idea of this, and to show it wasn&#8217;t local to UVA, quote from Flannery O&#8217;Connor&#8217;s 29 May 1959 letter (to T. R. Spivey): &#8220;Week before last I went to Wesleyan and read A Good Man Is Hard To Find.  After it I went to one of the classes where I was asked questions.  There were a couple of young teachers there and one of them, an earnest type, started asking the questions. ëMiss O&#8217;Connor,&#8217; he said, ëwhy was the Misfit&#8217;s hat black?&#8217;  I said most countrymen in Georgia wore black hats.  He looked pretty disappointed.  Then he said, ëMiss O&#8217;Connor, the Misfit represents Christ, does he not?&#8217;  He does not[.&#8217; H]e said, what it is the significance of the Misfit&#8217;s hat?&#8217;  I said it was to cover his head; and after that he left me alone.  Anyway, that&#8217;s what&#8217;s happening to the teaching of literature.&#8221;  (Lib of America Collected O&#8217;C, ed Sally Fitzgerald, pp. 1097-98)
			Should I try to quantify how many of the questions actually come from students?  Fewer than you&#8217;d suspect from the title of the published F in the University ñ and very few students apparently ever visited him during the office hours he faithfully kept
			But maybe end this with alum saying opened a window??
			</p>
	</div>
			<ul class="gallery">
				<li><a href="corks5701.jpg" rel="group1"><img src="corks5701t.jpg" alt="1957 YEARBOOK: STUDENTS CHANGING CLASSES" title="1957 YEARBOOK: STUDENTS CHANGING CLASSES" /></a></li>
				<li><a href="corks5702.jpg" rel="group1"><img src="corks5702t.jpg" alt="1957 YEARBOOK: CLASSES TITLEPAGE" title="1957 YEARBOOK: CLASSES TITLEPAGE" /></a></li>
				<li><a href="corks5704.jpg" rel="group1"><img src="corks5704t.jpg" alt="1957 YEARBOOK: DKE FRATERNITY" title="1957 YEARBOOK: DKE FRATERNITY" /></a></li>
				<li><a href="corks5705.jpg" rel="group1"><img src="corks5705t.jpg" alt="1957 YEARBOOK: WOMEN STUDENTS' ORGANIZATIONS" title="1957 YEARBOOK: WOMEN STUDENTS' ORGANIZATIONS" border="0" /></a></li>
				<li><a href="corks5706.jpg" rel="group1"><img src="corks5706t.jpg" alt="1957 YEARBOOK: EASTERS WEEKEND HIGHLIGHTS" title="1957 YEARBOOK: EASTERS WEEKEND HIGHLIGHTS" /></a></li>
				<li><a href="corks5707.jpg" rel="group1"><img src="corks5707t.jpg" alt="1957 YEARBOOK: FOOTBALL WEEKENDS" title="1957 YEARBOOK: FOOTBALL WEEKENDS" border="0" /></a></li>
				<li><a href="corks5708.jpg" rel="group1"><img src="corks5708t.jpg" alt="1957 YEARBOOK: OPENINGS WEEKEND" title="1957 YEARBOOK: OPENINGS WEEKEND" border="0" /></a></li>
				<li><a href="corks5709.jpg" rel="group1"><img src="corks5709t.jpg" alt="1957 YEARBOOK: IMAGES OF SOCIAL LIFE" title="1957 YEARBOOK: IMAGES OF SOCIAL LIFE" border="0" /></a></li>
				<li><a href="corks5710.jpg" rel="group1"><img src="corks5710t.jpg" alt="1957 YEARBOOK: MIDWINTERS WEEKEND" title="1957 YEARBOOK: MIDWINTERS WEEKEND" border="0" /></a></li>
				<li><a href="corks5711.jpg" rel="group1"><img src="corks5711t.jpg" alt="1957 YEARBOOK: IMAGES FROM THE YEAR" title="1957 YEARBOOK: IMAGES FROM THE YEAR" border="0" /></a></li>
				<li><a href="corks5801.jpg" rel="group1"><img src="corks5801t.jpg" alt="1958 YEARBOOK: EASTERS WEEKEND" title="1958 YEARBOOK: EASTERS WEEKEND" border="0" /></a></li>
				
				
					<li><a href="corks5802.jpg" rel="group1"><img src="corks5802t.jpg" alt="1958 YEARBOOK: FOOTBALL WEEKENDS" title="1958 YEARBOOK: FOOTBALL WEEKENDS" border="0" /></a></li>
					<li><a href="corks5803.jpg" rel="group1"><img src="corks5803t.jpg" alt="1958 YEARBOOK: SCENES FROM STUDENT LIFE" title="1958 YEARBOOK: SCENES FROM STUDENT LIFE" border="0" /></a></li>
					<li><a href="corks5804.jpg" rel="group1"><img src="corks5804t.jpg" alt="1958 YEARBOOK: STUDENT LEADERS" title="1958 YEARBOOK: STUDENT LEADERS" border="0" /></a></li>
					<li><a href="corks5805.jpg" rel="group1"><img src="corks5805t.jpg" alt="1958 YEARBOOK: JEFFERSON SOCIETY" title="1958 YEARBOOK: JEFFERSON SOCIETY" border="0" /></a></li>
					<li><a href="corks5901.jpg" rel="group1"><img src="corks5901t.jpg" alt="1958 YEARBOOK: FAULKNER AND TRACK TEAM" title="1959 YEARBOOK: FAULKNER AND TRACK TEAM" border="0" /></a></li>
			</ul>
			
			<div id="corks5704" class="hidden">
				<p><em>Below</em>: Delta Kappa Epsilon fraternity, from <i>Corks &amp; Curls</i>, the UVA yearbook (1957 edition, vol. 69, p. 85).</p>
				<p>
					<img src="corks5704.jpg" title="1957 YEARBOOK PHOTO" alt="1957 YEARBOOK PHOTO" />
				</p>
			</div>
			
			<div id="cavdaily23" class="hidden">
				<h3>The Cavalier Daily 22 May 1957</h3>
				<h4>Desegregation at the University</h4>
				<p>Last year's Student Council drafted a statement setting forth their position regarding social integration of the white and Negro races in University-connected activities (See text of statement on Page 1). The document has just been released for publication.</p>
				<p>From beginning to end, this Council paper exhibits calm judgement which makes it a refreshing change from much of what we hear relative to the problem of racial integration in the South today. Rather than try to write rules and regulations covering the situation, the Council calls for nothing more than wise discretion on the parts of all students.</p>
				<p>We feel that the success or failure of race relations at the University now rests largely in the hands of Negro students enrolled. Desegregation has gone over smoothly here because it has not been rushed by the colored race and because it has not caused social mixing between white and Negro. Even when the two have attended dances together in Memorial Gymnasium, there has been not the slightest hint of trouble or violence.</p>
				<p>Any attempt at exploiting this situation by either race will destroy this atmosphere of calm and good will and result in conflict which will bring both chaos and disgrace to the University. We hope that the same mature judgement and good sense will prevail in the future which we have witnessed in the past and that other colleges and universities will take note of the progress which this attitude has caused here. Both races can be justly proud of racial relations between students of this University.</p> 
			</div>
		</section>
		<section id="uva" title="UVa in the 1950s 2">
			<div id="essay_content">
				<h1 class="uppercase">UVA IN LATE FIFTIES</h1>
				
				<p><img src="uva50s01.jpg" align="left" hspace="8" border="0" alt="DETAIL: 1957 YEARBOOK PHOTO" title="DETAIL: 1957 YEARBOOK PHOTO" />In February 1957, when William Faulkner arrived in Charlottesville to occupy his position as Virginiaís first Writer-in-Residence, ìMr. Jeffersonís Universityî was 132 years old. Its first students matriculated in March 1825: 123 undergraduates, all white males.  There were almost five thousand UVA students by the 1956-1957 academic year, but they were still mostly white and male.  The Nursing Schoolís students were all female, the Education School was largely female, and there were a few women students in the graduate Schools of Law, Medicine and Arts and Sciences, but officially there were no women students in the College of Arts &amp; Sciences until 1969, and the College was not fully co-educational until the Class of 1976 arrived in 1972.  There actually are a few women pictured among the college students in the 1957 and 1958 editions of <i>Corks and Curls</i>, the school yearbook, but they might have been daughters of faculty members; during those years Mary Washington College, in Fredericksburg, was officially designated the stateís school for women.  (When Faulkner traveled there to speak in April 1957 he would still have been considered ìin-residenceî at UVA.)  A large number of the questions from Faulknerís UVA audiences come from women; in May 1957 he met with a group identified as ìWives of Law School Students,î and ìWivesî were invited to his session with the English Department faculty the same month, but since women only made up about 3% of the total student body, it is not clear who the women were during the other sessions, especially the classroom sessions.  Several were certainly graduate students in English (three are identified by name in his session with Stevensonís English 32), many were interested residents of Charlottesville or Albemarle County, still others may have been the wives of faculty members sitting in on classes when Faulkner was present.  These presence of these women suggests the environment at UVA wasnít as ìmaleî as it looks in the records.  To my ear, at least, the womenís voices we hear on the tapes donít sound shy or hesitant about being part of the conversation.</p>
				
				<p><a href="javascript:Start3('corks5704.html')"><img src="uva50s02.jpg" align="left" hspace="8" border="0" alt="DETAIL: PHOTO OF DELTA KAPPA EPSILON IN 1957 YEARBOOK" title="DETAIL: PHOTO OF DELTA KAPPA EPSILON IN 1957 YEARBOOK" /></a>On the other hand, I donít hear any recognizably ìblackî voices among the hundreds of people who ask Faulkner questions, and it seems likely that there were no blacks in any of his audiences here (though one man on the tapes identifies himself as an Indian national).  Thanks to the series of legal battles fought by the NAACP in the courtroom in the years leading up to the Supreme Courtís <i>Brown v Board of Education</i> decision, in the 1950s African American students began attending UVA in very small numbers: a few in the Law School, in Education and in Engineering.  I saw no sign of these students in <i>Corks and Curls</i> from the years Faulkner was here; the only black faces in those yearbooks belong either to the entertainers who came to town for the big weekends (Duke Ellington, Lionel Hampton, Louis Armstrong, among others) or to the servants who worked for the fraternities (identified in the group photos simply by their first names).   A May 1957 editorial in the student newspaper, <i>The Cavalier Daily</i>, titled ìDesegregation At The University,î refers to ìthe Negro students [now] enrolled,î but adds that there has not been any ìsocial mixing between white and Negroî at UVA, ìeven when the two have attended dances together in Memorial Gymnasium.î</p>
				
				<p><img src="uva50s03.jpg" align="left" hspace="8" border="0" alt="COVER: 1957 SPECTATOR JIM CROW ISSUE" title="COVER: 1957 SPECTATOR JIM CROW ISSUE" />The ìSupreme Court decisionî comes up several times in Faulknerís sessions at UVA, and no one has to explain which decision is being referred to.  You can hear the discussions that follow for yourself.  I sense a good deal of anxiety in the room whenever this subject is brought up, but very little openness to the possibility of social transformation.  The large number of news articles about school integration struggles throughout the South on the front pages of <i>The Cavalier Daily</i> between Fall 1956 and Spring 1958 suggests that white students were very interested in how traditional southern racial patterns might be changing, but in those same issues there is no discussion of admitting black students to the College.  Although UVA never seems to be included in the category of ìpublic schools,î a few voices were raised in the <i>CD</i> for school integration, belonging to some faculty members and one faculty wife (Sarah Boyle).  The paper defended the ìJim Crow Issueî published in May 1958 by <i>The Virginia Spectator</i>; in the issue this undergraduate monthly reprinted Faulknerís <i>Life</i> magazine ìLetter to the Northî and listed him as the ìmoderatorî of the debate staged between four newly-written articles, two pro-segregation and two pro-integration, none written by students (CD, 8 May 1957: 1, 2).  But most articles in the paper suggest how deeply the student body was loyal to the racial status quo.  When in May 1957 the <i>CD</i> decided to respond to a challenge from the Writer-in-Residence ñ ìWilliam Faulkner said yesterday, ëIíd like to see more undergraduates of this University express their opinions on topics of wide interestíî  (CD, 5 May 1957: 2) ñ by conducting a ìPoll on Integration,î students were given only two plans to choose between, and as the paper said, ìBoth plans have a common goal ñ prevention of racial integration in the public schools.î  (CD, 15 May 1957: 2) The plan that called for delaying tactics defeated the one that advocated vigorous defiance of the federal courts by two-to-one, but while one student wrote ìwe must have complete integrationî on his ballot (CD, 16 May 1957: 1) , and one student wrote the paper to complain that too few ballot boxes were available (CD, 17 May 1957: 2), no protests were registered about the narrow range of ìopinionsî the poll reflected.</p>
				
				<p><img src="uva50s04.jpg" align="left" hspace="8" border="0" alt="DETAIL: 1958 YEARBOOK PHOTO" title="DETAIL: 1958 YEARBOOK PHOTO" />One of the topics that Faulkner most frequently wants to give his own opinion about in the UVA sessions is ìthe pressure to conformî that he sees as among the most serious threats facing modern society.  He brought that concern with him to Virginia, but what he found at UVA probably only increased it.  These were what Robert Lowell called ìthe tranquilized Fifties,î and despite or because of Cold War fears about nuclear annihilation there was a widespread national longing for what journalists were calling ìnormalcy.î  Even so, the environment at UVA in the late 1950s exalted conformity ñ though the students called it ìtradition.î  The suit jackets and ties that students wore to all classes and public events as a kind of uniform were the outward and visible sign of a community that was comfortable with the world that they found themselves in, and devoted to the rituals of the previous generations of students.  ìGentlemanî was a word that resonated much more deeply with them than ìintellectualî or ìartist.î</p>
				
				<p><a href="javascript:Start3('faulknerABC.html')"><img src="uva50s05.jpg" align="left" hspace="8" border="0" alt="DETAIL: CD FAULKNER PHOTO" title="DETAIL: CD FAULKNER PHOTO" /></a>Faulknerís picture appears twice in the 1957 <i>Corks and Curls</i>, in the ìFeaturesî section.   Judging by the yearbookís annual emphases, however, the chief features of student life at UVA were fraternities, football games, and the three regularly occuring ìbig weekendsî ñ Openings, Mid-Winters, and Easters, supplemented by other annual events like the Beaux Arts Ball. For each of the three ìbigî weekends <i>The Cavalier Daily</i> published expanded editions, allowing them to list all the women (from other schools, of course) who would be attending, along with the names of their UVA dates.  Again to judge by the yearbookís photos, music and alcohol were the main ingredients of these weekends.  No one asked Faulkner during any of his sessions about Gowan Stevens, the character in <i>Sanctuary</i> who has just graduated from Virginia and canít stop talking about how heíd ìlearned in a good schoolî how to drink, which turns out to mean how to get drunk; if Faulknerís interrogators were embarrassed to bring Gowan up, though, the yearbook seems to celebrate displays of drunkenness.  This prevailing alcoholic culture makes it hard to know how to ìreadî the photograph <i>at left</i>, published on the front page of <i>The Cavalier Daily</i>'s "Mid-Winters Issue," which appeared the morning after Faulkner gave his speech exhorting Virginians to show the rest of the South the way toward integration ñ a picture of the Writer-in-Residence coming out of the liquor store with a paper bag in his hands (CD, 21 February 1958: 1).  Is it an attempt to undercut his message by suggesting it came out of a bottle of booze? or does it imply (especially since students would be stocking up their own bottles for the weekend) that Faulkner is ìone of usî?  (The photo was taken by Ken Ringle, who discusses it in his essay on Faulkner at UVA; in the first issue of the <i>CD</i> after the weekend, the paper ran an editorial about the speech, expressing disappointment with Faulknerís inadequacies as a speaker, but approving the way ìFaulkner's proposal [for improving Negro education] offers the compromise between the dogmatism of the North and the South on the subjectî [CD, 25 February 1958: 2].)</p>
				
				<p><a href="javascript:Start3('uvaenglish.html')"><img src="uvaenglisht.jpg" align="left" hspace="8" border="0" alt="DETAIL: ENGLISH DEPT IN 1960" title="DETAIL: ENGLISH DEPT IN 1960" /></a>Although probably only about half of the people who ask Faulkner questions on the tapes were UVA students, the most common setting for these sessions was an English Department class.  In 1957 and 1958 the departmentís faculty were also all white and male.</p>
				
				<p>and centered on the traditional   English lit, etc.  And one time Fís name appears in catalogue
					questionnaire on when F first studied?
					Can identify the time by large number of questions on symbols
					To give an idea of this, and to show it wasnít local to UVA, quote from Flannery OíConnorís 29 May 1959 letter (to T. R. Spivey): ìWeek before last I went to Wesleyan and read A Good Man Is Hard To Find.  After it I went to one of the classes where I was asked questions.  There were a couple of young teachers there and one of them, an earnest type, started asking the questions. ëMiss OíConnor,í he said, ëwhy was the Misfitís hat black?í  I said most countrymen in Georgia wore black hats.  He looked pretty disappointed.  Then he said, ëMiss OíConnor, the Misfit represents Christ, does he not?í  He does not[.í H]e said, what it is the significance of the Misfitís hat?í  I said it was to cover his head; and after that he left me alone.  Anyway, thatís whatís happening to the teaching of literature.î  (Lib of America Collected OíC, ed Sally Fitzgerald, pp. 1097-98)
					Should I try to quantify how many of the questions actually come from students?  Fewer than youíd suspect from the title of the published F in the University ñ and very few students apparently ever visited him during the office hours he faithfully kept
					But maybe end this with alum saying opened a window??
				</p> 
				
				
			</div>
			<div id="gallery">
				
				
				
			</div>
		</section>
		
	</page>
	
	<page id="about" slug="About" title="About William Faulkner">
		<section id="bio" title="Biography">
			<h3>Test image</h3>
			<img src="william-faulkner.jpg" alt="William Faulkner" title="William Faulkner" />
			
			<h3>Biography</h3>
			<p>He was born William Cuthbert Falkner in New Albany, Mississippi, the eldest son of
				Murry Cuthbert Falkner (August 17, 1870 – August 7, 1932) and Maud Butler (November
				27, 1871 – October 16, 1960). He later changed the spelling of his name to Faulkner.
				His brothers were Murry Charles "Jack" Falkner (June 26, 1899 – December 24, 1975),
				author John Falkner (later Faulkner) (September 24, 1901 – March 28, 1963) and Dean
				Swift Falkner (August 15, 1907 – November 10, 1935).</p>

			<p> Faulkner was raised in and heavily influenced by the state of Mississippi, as well
				as by the history and culture of the South as a whole. When he was four years old,
				his entire family moved to the nearby town of Oxford, where he lived on and off for
				the rest of his life. Oxford is the model for the town of "Jefferson" in his
				fiction, and Lafayette County, which contains the town of Oxford, is the model for
				his fictional Yoknapatawpha County. Faulkner's great-grandfather, William Clark
				Falkner, was an important figure in northern Mississippi who served as a colonel in
				the Confederate Army, founded a railroad, and gave his name to the town of Falkner
				in nearby Tippah County. He also wrote several novels and other works, establishing
				a literary tradition in the family. Colonel Falkner served as the model for Colonel
				John Sartoris in his great-grandson's writing. </p>
			<p> The elder Falkner was greatly influenced by the history of his family and the region
				in which they lived. Mississippi marked his sense of humor, his sense of the tragic
				position of blacks and whites, his characterization of Southern characters and
				timeless themes, including fiercely intelligent people dwelling behind the façades
				of good old boys and simpletons. Unable to join the United States Army because of
				his height, (he was 5' 5½"), Faulkner first joined the Canadian and then the British
				Royal Air Force, yet did not see any World War I wartime action. </p>
			<p> Faulkner himself made the change to his last name in 1918 upon joining the Air
				Force. But according to one story, a careless typesetter simply made an error. When
				the misprint appeared on the title page of Faulkner's first book and the author was
				asked about it, he supposedly replied, "Either way suits me."[2] Although Faulkner
				is heavily identified with Mississippi, he was living in New Orleans in 1925 when he
				wrote his first novel, Soldiers' Pay, after being influenced by Sherwood Anderson to
				try fiction. The small house at 624 Pirate's Alley, just around the corner from St.
				Louis Cathedral, is now the premises of Faulkner House Books, and also serves as the
				headquarters of the Pirate's Alley Faulkner Society. </p>
			<p> Faulkner served as Writer-in-Residence at the University of Virginia from 1957 until
				his death. In 1959 he suffered serious injuries in a horse-riding accident. Faulkner
				died of a heart attack at the age of 64 on July 6, 1962, at Wright's Sanitorium in
				Byhalia, Mississippi. </p>
		</section>
		<section id="california" title="In California">
			<h3>In California</h3>
			<p> In the early 1940s, Howard Hawks invited Faulkner to come to Hollywood to become a
				screenwriter for the films Hawks was directing. Faulkner happily accepted because he
				badly needed the money, and Hollywood paid well. Thus Faulkner contributed to the
				scripts for the films Hawks made from Raymond Chandler's The Big Sleep and Ernest
				Hemingway's To Have and Have Not. Faulkner became good friends with Hawks, the
				screenwriter A. I. Bezzerides, and the actors Humphrey Bogart and Lauren Bacall. </p>
			<p> An apocryphal story regarding Faulkner during his Hollywood years found him with a
				case of writer's block at the studio. He told Hawks he was having a hard time
				concentrating and would like to write at home. Hawks was agreeable, and Faulkner
				left. Several days passed, with no word from the writer. Hawks telephoned Faulkner's
				hotel and found that Faulkner had checked out several days earlier. It seems
				Faulkner had spoken quite literally, and had returned home to Mississippi to finish
				the screenplay. </p>
		</section>
	</page>
</site_info>
