<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<site_info>
	<title>Faulkner at Virginia</title>
	<index>
		<h2>Header</h2>
		<p>placeholder for index</p>
	</index>
	<browse>
		<list>
			<item>wfaudio01_1</item>
			<item>wfaudio01_2</item>
			<item>wfaudio02_1</item>
			<item>wfaudio02_2</item>
			<item>wfaudio03</item>
			<item>wfaudio04</item>
			<item>wfaudio05_1</item>
			<item>wfaudio05_2</item>
			<item>wfaudio06_1</item>
			<item>wfaudio06_2</item>
			<item>wfaudio07_1</item>
			<item>wfaudio07_2</item>
			<item>wfaudio08_1</item>
			<item>wfaudio08_2</item>
			<item>wfaudio09_1</item>
			<item>wfaudio09_2</item>
			<item>wfaudio10</item>
			<item>wfaudio11_1</item>
			<item>wfaudio11_2</item>
			<item>wfaudio12_1</item>
			<item>wfaudio12_2</item>
			<item>wfaudio12_3</item>
			<item>wfaudio13</item>
			<item>wfaudio14_1</item>
			<item>wfaudio14_2</item>
			<item>wfaudio15</item>
			<item>wfaudio16_1</item>
			<item>wfaudio16_2</item>
			<item>wfaudio17</item>
			<item>wfaudio18_1</item>
			<item>wfaudio18_2</item>
			<item>wfaudio18_3</item>
			<item>wfaudio19_1</item>
			<item>wfaudio19_2</item>
			<item>wfaudio20_1</item>
			<item>wfaudio20_2</item>
			<item>wfaudio21</item>
			<item>wfaudio22_1</item>
			<item>wfaudio22_2</item>
			<item>wfaudio23_1</item>
			<item>wfaudio23_2</item>
			<item>wfaudio24_1</item>
			<item>wfaudio24_2</item>
			<item>wfaudio25</item>
			<item>wfaudio26_1</item>
			<item>wfaudio26_2</item>
			<item>wfaudio27</item>
			<item>wfaudio28_1</item>
			<item>wfaudio28_2</item>
			<item>wfaudio29_1</item>
			<item>wfaudio29_2</item>
			<item>wfaudio30_1</item>
			<item>wfaudio30_2</item>
			<item>wfaudio31</item>
			<item>wfaudio32</item>
		</list>
		<text>
			<h2>Browse</h2>
		</text>
	</browse>
	<page id="about" slug="About" title="About William Faulkner">
		<section id="bio" title="Biography">
			<h1>Test image</h1>
			<img src="william-faulkner.jpg" alt="William Faulkner" title="William Faulkner" />
			
			<h3>Biography</h3>
			<p>He was born William Cuthbert Falkner in New Albany, Mississippi, the eldest son of
				Murry Cuthbert Falkner (August 17, 1870 – August 7, 1932) and Maud Butler (November
				27, 1871 – October 16, 1960). He later changed the spelling of his name to Faulkner.
				His brothers were Murry Charles "Jack" Falkner (June 26, 1899 – December 24, 1975),
				author John Falkner (later Faulkner) (September 24, 1901 – March 28, 1963) and Dean
				Swift Falkner (August 15, 1907 – November 10, 1935).</p>

			<p> Faulkner was raised in and heavily influenced by the state of Mississippi, as well
				as by the history and culture of the South as a whole. When he was four years old,
				his entire family moved to the nearby town of Oxford, where he lived on and off for
				the rest of his life. Oxford is the model for the town of "Jefferson" in his
				fiction, and Lafayette County, which contains the town of Oxford, is the model for
				his fictional Yoknapatawpha County. Faulkner's great-grandfather, William Clark
				Falkner, was an important figure in northern Mississippi who served as a colonel in
				the Confederate Army, founded a railroad, and gave his name to the town of Falkner
				in nearby Tippah County. He also wrote several novels and other works, establishing
				a literary tradition in the family. Colonel Falkner served as the model for Colonel
				John Sartoris in his great-grandson's writing. </p>
			<p> The elder Falkner was greatly influenced by the history of his family and the region
				in which they lived. Mississippi marked his sense of humor, his sense of the tragic
				position of blacks and whites, his characterization of Southern characters and
				timeless themes, including fiercely intelligent people dwelling behind the façades
				of good old boys and simpletons. Unable to join the United States Army because of
				his height, (he was 5' 5½"), Faulkner first joined the Canadian and then the British
				Royal Air Force, yet did not see any World War I wartime action. </p>
			<p> Faulkner himself made the change to his last name in 1918 upon joining the Air
				Force. But according to one story, a careless typesetter simply made an error. When
				the misprint appeared on the title page of Faulkner's first book and the author was
				asked about it, he supposedly replied, "Either way suits me."[2] Although Faulkner
				is heavily identified with Mississippi, he was living in New Orleans in 1925 when he
				wrote his first novel, Soldiers' Pay, after being influenced by Sherwood Anderson to
				try fiction. The small house at 624 Pirate's Alley, just around the corner from St.
				Louis Cathedral, is now the premises of Faulkner House Books, and also serves as the
				headquarters of the Pirate's Alley Faulkner Society. </p>
			<p> Faulkner served as Writer-in-Residence at the University of Virginia from 1957 until
				his death. In 1959 he suffered serious injuries in a horse-riding accident. Faulkner
				died of a heart attack at the age of 64 on July 6, 1962, at Wright's Sanitorium in
				Byhalia, Mississippi. </p>
		</section>
		<section id="california" title="In California">
			<h3>In California</h3>
			<p> In the early 1940s, Howard Hawks invited Faulkner to come to Hollywood to become a
				screenwriter for the films Hawks was directing. Faulkner happily accepted because he
				badly needed the money, and Hollywood paid well. Thus Faulkner contributed to the
				scripts for the films Hawks made from Raymond Chandler's The Big Sleep and Ernest
				Hemingway's To Have and Have Not. Faulkner became good friends with Hawks, the
				screenwriter A. I. Bezzerides, and the actors Humphrey Bogart and Lauren Bacall. </p>
			<p> An apocryphal story regarding Faulkner during his Hollywood years found him with a
				case of writer's block at the studio. He told Hawks he was having a hard time
				concentrating and would like to write at home. Hawks was agreeable, and Faulkner
				left. Several days passed, with no word from the writer. Hawks telephoned Faulkner's
				hotel and found that Faulkner had checked out several days earlier. It seems
				Faulkner had spoken quite literally, and had returned home to Mississippi to finish
				the screenplay. </p>
		</section>
	</page>
</site_info>
